Guide to the Few Family Papers, 1861-2009 (bulk 1905-1967) UA.03.55.0002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Miscellaneous, circa 1879-1970
  - Miscellaneous, 1899, 1905-1908, undated (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1914-1965, undated (Box 19)
  - William Preston Few scrapbook of clippings (Box 20)
  - Address books/Memo books belonging to Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1899, 1922, undated (Box 20)
  - The Scribble-in Book which contains names and addresses (Box 20)
  - 1906 Trinity College/Duke University Reunion Badge (Box 20)
  - Delegate Badge to the Deep Waterway Convention in New Orleans, La., 1906 Oct. 30-Nov. 12 (Box 20)
- Political Papers of Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1942-1970
  This series consists of the correspondence, memorabilia, pamphlets, clippings, photographs, and printed materials amassed by Few in her capacity as a leader in the Republican Party of North Carolina at the national and state level. Items include materials concerning N.C. state politics, campaign strategies, political support, the New Deal and other issues; photos of Philadelphia hotels; a copy of Eisenhower's 1955 State of the Union Address; cards from prominent Republicans; and Republican Party news releases. Printed matter highlights the national conventions, and includes such items as hand-outs, souvenir volumes, buttons saying "I LIKE IKE," "I'M DAFT ABOUT TAFT," and "IT'S TIME FOR NIXON," and documents on the workings of a presidential campaign.
  - Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, 1948-1951 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, 1952 Feb.-Aug. (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, 1952 Sept.-Dec. (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1958, 1976 (Box 29)
    Includes correspondence from Richard M. Nixon.
  - Correspondence, 1952-1970, undated (Box 29)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1970, undated (Box 21)
  - Addresses and Writings, 1943-1965 (Box 21)
  - Addresses and Writings, 1948-1956, undated (Box 21)
  - Christmas Cards [arranged alphabetically], A-L (Box 21)
  - Christmas Cards [arranged alphabetically], M-R (Box 21)
  - Christmas Cards [arranged alphabetically], S-W (Box 22)
  - Dwight D. Eisenhower Postcards, undated (Box 22)
  - Dwight D. Eisenhower Photograph, undated (Box 22)
  - Dwight D. Eisenhower Talking Photo Commemorating his Inauguration, 1953 (Box 22)
  - Dwight D. and Mamie Eisenhower Photograph [color], undated (Box 22)
  - Dwight D. Eisenhower and Mary Reamey Thomas Few Photograph, undated (Box 22)
  - Richard M. Nixon, Mary Reamey Thomas Few and Randolph Reamey Few Photograph, [1952?] (Box 22)
  - Philadelphia, Pa. Photographs, circa 1948 (Box 22)
  - National Republican Convention [Philadelphia, Pa.] Photograph, circa 1948 (Box 22)
  - Hotel Walt Whitman [Camden, NJ], Photograph, circa 1948 (Box 22)
  - Valley Forge [Pa.] Photographs, circa 1948 (Box 22)
  - Robert Alphonso Taft Photograph [autographed], undated (Box 22)
  - Photos (go with political scrapbook), 1948-1952, undated (Box 29)
  - Political Articles, 1946-1956 (Box 29)
  - Clippings, 1944-1964, undated (2 folders) (Box 22)
  - Clippings, 1952-1956 (Box 29)
  - Printed Material, 1942-1944 (Box 22)
  - Printed Material, 1945-1946 (Box 22)
  - Printed Material, 1947-1949 (Box 22)
  - Printed Material, 1950-1951 (Box 22)
  - Printed Material, 1952 Jan.-July (Box 23)
  - Printed Material, 1952 Aug.-Dec. (Box 23)
  - Printed Material, 1953 (Box 23)
  - Printed Material, 1954-1964, undated (Box 23)
  - National Republican Congressional Convention Campaign Speech Kit, 1954 (Box 23)
  - Annual Assay Commission, 1953 (Box 23)
  - 25th Republican National Convention Program [Chicago, Il.], 1952 July 7 (Box 23)
  - Republican Almanac, 1948 (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 23)
  - Convention Name Tags, Badges, and Pins (Box 24)
  - Elephant Figurines (Box 25)
  - Campaign Buttons (Box 26)
  - Campaign Ribbons, Banners, Stickers and Tickets (Box 26)
  - Eisenhower License Plates (Box 26)
  - Oversize Photograph of Douglas MacArthur (Box 26)
- Family Materials, 5
  The Family Materials subseries contains photographs, memorabilia, business papers, clippings, certificates and diplomas, and other materials collected by William Preston Few, Mary Randolph Few, and their sons. Materials include notebooks kept by William Preston Few during his English classes at Harvard University, bound books owned by family members, childhood items belonging to Yancy and Kendrick Few, Mary Reamey Thomas Few's 1911 "Bride's Book," and files relating to William Preston Few's involvement with meetings and assemblies of the Methodist Church. The series also includes cast photographs and Mary Reamey Thomas Few's copy of the script for "The Dukes," a play about the Duke family performed in 1964.
  Materials are arranged by family member, then chronologically.
  - William P. Few: Diplomas, 1893-1911 (Box 32)
  - William P. Few: 18th Century Literature (notebook), 1894-1895 (Box 29)
  - William P. Few: Elizabethan Drama (notebook), 1895-1896 (Box 29)
  - William P. Few: Course Notebooks, 1896, undated (Box 29)
  - William P. Few: "Valuable Papers" Holder, 1911 (Box 29)
    Includes handwritten "Last Will and Testament"
  - William P. Few: Certificates, 1920-1936 (Box 32)
  - William P. Few: Photographs, 1922-2000, undated (Box 29)
    Includes photograph and biographical information about Benjamin Franklin Few, father of William P. Few
  - William P. Few: Methodist Conference Nametags, 1924, 1939 (Box 34)
  - William P. Few: Writings, Clippings, Photographs, and Memorabilia, 1928-1940, 1991, undated (Box 29)
  - William P. Few: Methodist Conference: Handbooks, 1939, 1940 (Box 29)
  - William P. Few: Methodist Conference: New York, 1939 June (Box 29)
  - William P. Few: Methodist Conference: Talk by William P. Few, Lake Junaluska, NC, 1940 August 12 (Box 29)
  - William P. Few: Methodist Conference: Church Conference in Nashville, TN, 1940 August 30 (Box 29)
  - William P. Few: Methodist Conference: Meeting of Board of Education, Methodist Church, Chicago, 1940 (Box 29)
  - William P. Few: In Memoriam Book, 1940 (Box 29)
  - William P. Few: Clippings and obituaries, 1940; 2 folders (Box 29)
  - William P. Few: Clippings about death of William P. Few, 1940 (Box 32)
  - William P. Few: Wallpaper samples, undated (Box 32)
  - William P. Few: Desk Nameplate, undated (Box 34)
  - Mary Reamey Thomas Few: Certificates, 1905 (Box 32)
  - Mary Reamey Thomas Few: Bride Book, circa 1911 (Box 29)
  - Mary Reamey Thomas Few: Clippings, 1914-1953 (Box 29)
  - Mary Reamey Thomas Few: Clipppings and Memorabilia, 1924-1999, undated (Box 29)
  - Mary Reamey Thomas Few: Awards and Tributes, 1966-1971, undated (Box 29)
  - Mary Reamey Thomas Few's copy of "The Dukes" Script and Cast Photographs, 1964 (Box 29)
  - Mary Reamey Thomas Few: "Letters, Papers, Publications, Photographs, and Memorabilia Saved by Mary R. Few": A Report by K. S. Few, 1990 June (Box 29)
  - Yancy Preston Few, 1922-1931, 1989, undated (Box 30)
  - Yancy Preston Few: Nature Book, undated (Box 30)
  - Kendrick Sheffield Few: Items Belonging to Kendrick Sheffield Few, 1917-1938, 1992 (Box 30)
  - Kendrick Sheffield Few: Camp Sequoyah, 1928, undated (Box 30)
  - Kendrick Sheffield Few: Mary Toms Newsom Ward ('38), 1936, 1962-1964 (Box 30)
  - Kendrick Sheffield Few: Rhodes Scholarship Application Information, 1938 (Box 30)
  - Kendrick Sheffield Few: Clippings, 1938, 1974-1989 (Box 30)
  - Kendrick Sheffield Few: Trinity College Grades, Senior Year, 1939 (Box 30)
  - Kendrick Sheffield Few: Duke University, 1939 (Box 30)
  - Kendrick Sheffield Few: Items Belonging to Kendrick Sheffield Few, 1985-1996 (Box 30)
  - Kendrick Sheffield Few: Photographs, circa 1917-1995 (Box 30)
  - Kendrick Sheffield Few: Photographs: Commencement, 1937-1939 (Box 30)
  - Kendrick Sheffield Few: Degrees and Certificates, 1942, 1960, 1990 (Box 32)
  - Kendrick Sheffield Few: Photographs, 1943-1945 (Box 30)
  - Kendrick Sheffield Few: Photographs, 1945-1959, undated (Box 30)
  - Kendrick Sheffield Few: Photographs, 1957-1977 (Box 30)
  - Kendrick Sheffield Few: Photographs, Longtime Friend and Golf Buddy Walter Barlow, 1981-1991 (Box 30)
  - Kendrick and Randolph Few: Note and NC Historical Review Copies to Ran Few and Ken Few from Bob Durden, 1987-1989 (Box 30)
  - Randolph Reamey Few: Photograph Album, 1920-2006 (Box 33)
    Album created for Randolph Few by his daughter, Dana Few Pope; includes photographs of the entire Few family, including Mary Reamey Thomas Few as a child, as well as photographs of the Trinity College campus (now East Campus) and Benjamin N. Duke and Sarah Angier Duke.
  - Randolph Reamey Few: Photographs, 1922-1996, undated (Box 30)
  - Photographs: Few Family Members, 1891-1954, undated (Box 30)
  - Clippings and Memorabilia, circa 1903, 1914-1920, 1990, undated (Box 30)
    Includes letter written by William P. Few regarding Basset Affair
  - Memorabilia: William P. Few, Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1905, 1940, undated (Box 30)
  - Publications, 1909-1934 (Box 32)
  - Clippings and publications, 1914-1930 (Box 32)
  - Photographs: Unclassified, with identification, 1924-1970, undated (Box 30)
  - Estate and Farm Loan and Purchase Papers, 1925-1950 (Box 30)
  - Publications: North Carolina Christian Advocate, 1925-1948 (Box 32)
  - Pamphlets, Clippings, and Memorabilia, 1932-1942, undated (Box 30)
  - Clippings and publications, 1932-1958, undated (Box 32)
  - Annual Report: Durham, North Carolina, 1951-1952 (Box 30)
  - Photographs: Few Family, 1959-1961, undated (Box 32)
  - Photographs: no identification, undated (Box 30)
- Duke University Materials, 6
  The Duke University Materials series contains photographs, magazines, newspaper clippings, correspondence, booklets and brochures, and other items relating to the history of Duke University and Trinity College. These were collected by members of the Few family, primarily Mary Reamey Thomas Few. Materials include writings by William Preston Few; clippings about President Few or the establishment of Duke University; booklets about campus clubs and fraternities; and information about memorials established for President Few and some members of the Duke family after their deaths.
  Materials are arranged chronologically.
  - 1906 Graduating Class Album (Mary Reamey Thomas Few's class) (Box 30)
  - Trinity College Annual Catalog, 1906-1907 (Box 30)
  - Booklets with images of Trinity College and Duke University, 1911, 1923, 1929 (Box 32)
  - Clippings, 1922-1935 (Box 32)
  - Trinity College Regulations Governing Absences, undated (Box 30)
  - Photographs, maps, clippings, 1920s-1989 (Oversize-folder 1)
    Includes a panoramic photograph of President William P. Few, Benjamin N. Duke, Governor William Walton Kitchin, and many other individuals, likely presidents of colleges and universities around the United States, undated; also includes a drawing labeled "Duke University General Plan," undated, circa 1920s.
  - 1906 Class Reunion, 1926 (Box 30)
  - Coach Wallace Wade, Football Programs, 1928-1945 (Box 30)
  - Duke Fraternity Materials, general, 1935-1942 (Box 30)
  - Programs, brochures, booklets, bulletin, 1935-1975 (Box 31)
  - Phi Delta Theta, 1941-1948 (Box 31)
  - Secret Order of the Red Friar, 1942 (Box 31)
  - Clippings, 1949-1951, undated (Box 32)
  - 1943 Class Reunions, 1959-2003; 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Campus Club, 1998, 2012, undated (Box 31)
  - Duke Family: Materials in memoriam of James Buchanan Duke, 1925-1928 (Box 31)
  - Duke Family: Materials in memoriam of Benjamin Newton Duke, 1929, 1999 (Box 31)
  - Duke Family: Dedication of Artelia Roney Duke Science Building at Elon College, 1927 (Box 31)
  - Publications by/about the Few Family and Duke University, 1912-1991; 6 folders (Box 31)
  - Clippings: William P. Few, 1927-1943 (Box 31)
  - Clippings and Publications, 1927-1939, undated; 2 folders (Box 31)
  - William Preston Few Memorial Scholarship Fund, 1972-1984 (Box 31)
  - 50th Anniversary of William P. Few's Death: ceremony in Duke Chapel, 1990 (Box 31)
  - Historical Marker in Honor of William P. Few in Jackson Grove, South Carolina, 1997 (Box 31)
  - Wofford College Organ Dedication, 1998 (Box 31)
  - William P. Few Bust in Allen Building, 2004 (Box 31)
  - William P. Few Interfaith Chapel, Durham, 2005 (Box 31)
  - William P. Few Endowment for the Duke Chapel, 2005-2009 (Box 31)